乔伊  快说啦
Come on Joey!!!
瑞秋  我知道的昨晚都告诉你了
Rach, I told you everything I knew last night!
没什么大不了的
Look, it's not that big of a deal,
莫妮卡和钱德勒只不过在"办事"
so Monica and Chandler are doing it.
真不敢相信你居然这么说
I can't believe you would say that!
抱歉  莫妮卡和钱德勒在"做爱"
Sorry. Monica and Chandler are making love.
不是  我是说  这是件大事
No! I mean come on! This is a huge deal!
我想知道细节
Fine I want-I need more details,
是谁先吻谁的
who-who initiated the first kiss?
不知道
I don't know.
他跟她在一起时浪漫吗
Is he romantic with her?
不知道
I don't know.
他们相爱吗
Are they in love?
不知道
I don't know.
你什么都不知道
You don't know anything.
-我知道一件事  -什么
- Ohh, I know one thing! - What?
他们在这张沙发上做过
They did it right there on the couch.
-罗斯  -行啦
- Hey Ross. - Yeah.
甘瑟  请给我一个英式松饼
Hey Gunther, can I have a scone please?
想听好消息吗
Wanna hear some good news?
我认识的某人要结婚了
Someone I know is getting married!
婚礼是最开心的场合
Yeah! And weddings are happy occasions!
对了  那人是我的前妻艾蜜莉
Oh, by-the-by it's my ex-wife Emily!
-什么  -别难过  伙计
- What? - Oh! Sorry man.
你的英式松饼
Here's your scone.
谢谢  甘瑟
Oh, thanks Gunther.
白痴英国点心
Stupid British snack food!!!!!!!
这是情绪管理课教的吗
Did they teach you that in your anger management class?
知道怎么做会有帮助吗
Hey, you know what might help you deal with it?
你就这么想
Think of it this way,
你和艾蜜莉已经过去了
you and Emily are in the past
你不能为过去的事生气
and you can't be mad about the past.
你还气我们跟法国买土地吗
So are you still mad about the Louisiana Purchase?
菲比  没有人会气那个
Pheebs, I don't think anyone's mad about that.
没错  因为已经过去了
Exactly! Because it's in the past!
那个有人要吃吗
Anybody gonna eat that?
我们盛装参加公司宴会耶
Look at us all dressed up for the big office party!
对了  是为了庆祝什么
By the way, what are we celebrating?
圣诞派对后剩下很多酒水
Oh, we had a lot of liquor left over from the Christmas party.
真是太好了  熟悉的朋友都不会来
I think this is so cool because none of our friends are here
我们可以正大光明  不必躲躲藏藏了
and we can be a real couple. We don't have to hide.
没错  我可以这样
I know, I can do this.
而我可以这样
Ooh, and I can do this.
我们不能那样
We can't do that.
嘿  宾
Hey Bing!
这位美女是谁
Wo-ho-ho, who's the pretty lady
怎么会跟你在一起
and what the hell is she doing with you?
我也这样问自己
I asked myself that very question, sir.
这位是莫妮卡  我上司道格
Uh,  this is Monica. This is my boss, Doug.
道格  这是莫妮卡
Doug this is Monica.
很高兴见到你
Hi, nice to meet you!
你好  这是我妻子卡拉
Hi! And this is my wife Kara.
很高兴见到你  莫妮卡  宾
Nice to meet you Monica. Bing!
宾  你听说了
Say uh, Bing, did you hear
公司找了新的法律顾问公司吗
about the new law firm we got working for us?
-没有  -骗他们-坑他们-跑路事务所
- No, sir. - Yeah, Dickem, Stickem & Run.
走吧  亲爱的  我们去喝个痛快
Come on honey, let's go drink our body weight.
-你这是做什么  -什么
- What was that? - What?
你刚才发出的嗓音
That noise you just made?
那是我的应酬笑法
Oh, that was my work laugh.
应酬笑法
Really? Your work laugh?
这种派对上要想受欢迎
Oh, believe me, to survive this party,
非得来这一手不可
you're gonna have to come up with one too.
-好吧  看我的  -好
- All right, check me out. - Okay.
三十块吧  神父  等同市价
...says $30 Father; same as in town.
同事们都对你昨晚的表现赞不绝口
Hey! Everybody at work loved you last night!
真的吗
Really?
而且他们因为你而更喜欢我了
And! They like me more just because I was with ya!
你弥补了不少乔伊造成的伤害
I think you repaired a lot of the damage from when they met Joey.
道格还找我们打网球
And Doug wants us to play tennis with them.
工作时间以外他根本就不理我
He's never even talked to me outside of work.
除了那次在
Except for that time
脱衣舞夜总会碰到他
when we bumped into each other at that strip club.
脱衣舞教堂
Strip church.
总之  我要去找一支球拍
Anyway, I'm gonna go try and find a racquet.
你不是有一支吗
Hey, I thought you already had one.
以前有  但乔伊认为
Oh I used too, but then Joey thought it would be fun
拿去中央公园敲石头会更有趣
to go to Central Park and hit rocks at...bigger rocks.
瑞秋  你有网球拍吗
Hey Rach, do you have a tennis racquet?
借给乔伊了  就再没见过
Oh umm, y'know I lent it to Joey and I never actually got it back.
那祝你好运
Okay, good luck with that.
怎么样
What's up?!
你怎么来了  今天不是要盘点吗
What are you doing here? I thought you had to do inventory all day.
没错  但我决定午休久一点
Well yeah, I do, but you know I decided to
好好陪陪我的朋友莫妮卡
I'd take a long lunch and spend some time with my friend Monica.
我们现在很少谈心了
Y'know I-I feel that we don't talk anymore.
你好吗  有什么新变化
How are you? What is new with you?
不多  工作很顺利
Uhh, not much. Uh, work's good.
我们不必聊工作
Oh y'know what, we don't have to talk about work.
什么都可以聊
We can talk about anything!
好的
Okay. Umm...
不如这样  谈谈男女关系
Hey! Y'know what? Let's talk about relationships!
你最近怎样
Okay, what's going on with you?
没人追  该你了
Nothing! You go!
我原本觉得银行有一个人很帅
Well, I-I-there was this guy at the bank that I thought was cute
现在不觉得了
umm, but I don't anymore.
真精彩
Wow that's uh, juicy.
不过  莫妮卡
Umm,  y'know what though Mon,
我确实很忙
I actually do have a lot of work to do
你确定没别的了吗
so if-if-are you sure there's just not anything else?
确定
Yes, I'm sure!
瑞秋  你有什么事想说吗
Rachel is there something that you want to talk me about?
没有
No!
有也不告诉你
If there was I wouldn't tell you.
好  然后呢
Okay, then what happened?
是嘛  待会才轮到你
Ohh. Uh-huh. Uh-huh. You'll get your turn!
菲比  在干嘛
Hey Pheebs, what's going on?
没什么  这事还没完
Nothing! This is not over!
-不好  -怎么了
- No! No! No! - What?!
我熬了一整晚写信骂艾蜜莉
I was up all night writing this really nasty letter to Emily!
相当完美  现在却沾满...
It was perfect and now it's all covered in-in...
多谢了
Actually, thanks!
准备好去看电影了吗
All right! Everybody ready to go to the movies?
我不想去了
Uh actually, I think I'm gonna skip it.
真的吗
Really?
我想留下看书
Yeah, I'm gonna stay and read my book.
现在只想一个人待着
I just wanna be alone right now.
真不想去吗
Oh. Are you sure you don't want to come?
汤姆·汉克斯  梅格·瑞恩
Tom Hanks, Meg Ryan,
他俩写电邮什么的
they get mail and stuff.
不看了  乔伊
That's okay, Joe.
我们走  菲比
All right, let's go Pheebs.
老天
Oh, God!
赢了
Game!
说真的  宾
Well, I gotta tell ya Bing;
你的搭档真是个母老虎
that partner of yours is a real tiger.
-你还好吗  亲爱的  -不行了
- Are you all right sweethart? - I'm not all right.
我们去喝点水
We're, we're just gonna get a little sip of water.
我今天很在状态吧
Am I on fire today or what?!
他俩简直就是待宰的羔羊
Those birds are browned, basted, and ready to be carved!
放轻松  马丁娜
Okay, easy Martina.
下一局我们该让他们赢
I think we should let them win the next game.
抱歉  我不懂你说什么
I'm sorry, I don't understand what you just said.
让他们赢一次吧
Let them win one.
你疯了吗  我们吃定他们了
Are you crazy?! We own those two!
看他们那熊样儿
I mean look at 'um,
他喘不过气  而她都在磕药了
he can't breath and she's popping pills.
你一点机会都不给他们
You're not even giving them a chance!
他们有球拍不是吗
They have racquets don't they?!
宾  我们再打最后一局吧
Uh Bing, I think we're gonna make this the last game.
了解  我求之不得
Oh yes, sir! Put me out of my misery.
你真的没打过职业比赛吗
Are you sure you never played pro?
拜托让他们赢吧
Please let them win!
那我就使九成五的劲  最大的让步了
I'll take it down to 95% but that's the best I can do.
哎呀  没击中
Oopsey, missed it!
我接到了
I got it!
好球
Nice shot.
我来
I got it!!
出界
Long!
真不敢相信你居然让他们赢了
I can't believe you let them win!
至少你把不爽掩饰得很好
Yeah, at least you hid your feelings well about it.
我很沮丧
I was frustrated.
这是我的球拍
It was my racquet.
是你让我沮丧的
I was frustrated with you!
如果没输那场球
If we hadn't lost the game
他们也不会请我们明晚去吃饭
they never would've invented us to dinner tomorrow night.
我最困扰的是
Y'know what really bothers me?
你在他们身边整个人都变了
It-it's how-how different you act around them!
故意输球  假笑
I mean y'know the throwing the tennis games, the fake laugh,
回头见  宾
the "I'll see you around, Bing!"
除非我先回头  道格
"Not if I see you first, Doug!"
告诉你  我不喜欢工作的钱德勒
I gotta tell you, I don't like Work Chandler.
他是个马屁精
Okay? The guy's a suck-up.
因为你这些话  我今晚在床上不会尽力的
Okay y'know what, because you said that, I'm not putting out tonight.
告诉你们  肯定出事了
I'm telling you, something's wrong!
我哥不会彻夜不归的
My brother does not stay out all night.
也许我们该找找垃圾道
Maybe we should check the trash chute.
垃圾道装不下罗斯
Ross couldn't fit down the trash chute.
对  差一点
That's right, he almost could.
上次我就卡在那里了
Which is exactly how I got stuck there.
他回来了
Hey! There he is!
我的天
Oh my God!
你死到哪里去了
Where the hell have you been?!!
就是去外面了
Just, y'know out.
外面  天哪
Ohh, out, oh God,
我们怎么没去那里找
I don't know why we didn't think to check there!
你做什么去了
What were you doing?
我去了酒吧
I uh, went to a bar.
然后  到处转了转
And then I just uh, just walked around for a while.
你独自一人在街上转悠了一晚上
You walked around all night in the city by yourself?
他有艳遇
He hooked up!
搭上什么妞了
He hooked up with someone.
我没必要什么都向你们报告
Look, I don't have to answer your questions!
我是成年人  我爱干嘛就干嘛
Okay? I'm a big boy, I can do whatever I want!
他有艳遇
He hooked up!!
跟我们说说她的事
Tell us about her!
罗斯  你忘了围巾
Ross you left you scarf in...
大家好
Hey you guys.
好了  好了
Okay, okay.
我知道你们怎么想  但钱德勒远在也门
I know what you all are thinking. But Chandler is in Yemen!
我还年轻  我有需要  我不能永远等下去
I'm a young woman! I have needs! I can't wait forever!
是啊  我也是这么想的
Yeah! No that's what I was thinking.
所以我请你们  在批评我之前先想一下
So I'm asking you please, take a moment before you judge me.
没有人批评你
Oh, nobody's judging you.
你  天时地利人和先生
Oh! Okay! You, Mister Right Place at the Right Time,
打电话给我
call me!
我知道你们要说什么
Okay, look, I-I know what you guys are going to say...
你们的孩子会非常可怕
You two will have very hairy children.
我不知道你会说这个
Okay, I didn't know you would say that.
罗斯  珍妮斯
Ross! Janice?!
够了  打住
All right, hold on! Hold on. Hold on.
这是罗斯  他是我们的朋友
This is Ross, okay? He's our friend.
他显然是疯了  失去了理智
He obviously went crazy. He obviously lost his mind.
没那么夸张  好吗
Look, it's not that crazy. Okay?
珍妮斯和我有很多共同点
Janice and I have a lot in common!
我们都离过婚  我们都有小孩
We've-we've both been divorced. We-we both have kids.
你真的要再见她吗
So are you actually gonna see her again?
菲比  别让他有这样的想法
Phoebe! Don't put ideas in his head!
我确实要再见她
I am gonna see her again.
都怪你  菲比
Damn it Phoebe!!
好吧  我得告诉你
Okay, I have to tell you something
一件我从来没承认过的事情
that I have never admitted during our entire friendship!
高中时  明知你喜欢詹姆斯·拉法瑞
But, when we were in high school I made out with James Farrell
我还是跟他亲热过
even when I knew that you liked him!
一吐为快太爽了  该你说了
Wow, that feels so good to get off my chest! Okay, you go!
该我了  你说什么
My turn? What-what are you talking about?
莫妮卡  我知道你和钱德勒的事
Ugh, Monica, I know about you and Chandler.
-什么  -我那天听到你们在讲电话
- What?! - I overheard you guys on the phone the other day,
你说  "我就跟瑞秋讲
and you said, "I'll just tell Rachel
我要去洗几小时衣服"
that I'm doing laundry for a couple of hours."
他说  "洗衣服  我的新绰号吗"
And he said, "Laundry? Is that my new nickname?"
然后你说  "你知道你的新绰号
And you said, "No! You know what your nickname is,
大先生"
Mr. Big."
原来你在写剧本啊  瑞秋
Well. Sounds like you're writing yourself a little play there Rach.
记得把结局告诉我
Wow! Let me know how that one turns out.
我不知道  因为我吓坏了
Well, I wouldn't know because I got so freaked out
把电话挂掉了
that I hung up the phone.
如果你听完
Well, if you had kept listening,
你就会听到我叫他大  傻帽
you-you would have heard me call him Mr. Big......ot.
-什么  -大傻帽
- What?! - Mr. Bigot.
他讲了些种族主义的笑话
He tells the most racist jokes.
就是这样吗  你是说
All right. So that's it. You're telling me
你和钱德勒之间没什么
that there is nothing going on between you and Chandler.
我和钱德勒
Me and Chandler?!
你放上二十块
All right, put your 20 bucks down.
谁先找到好吃的谁赢  好吗
First one to find the tasty treat wins. Okay?
好了  请参赛者从隔离间出场
All right. Let's get the contestants out of their isolation booths.
它们出场了
And they're off!
别挡住我的参赛者  裁判
Get your foot off my contestant! Judge!
裁判判定没有违规
Judge rules, no violation.
-伙计们  -嘿
- Hey guys!  - Hey!
知道吗  说来奇怪
Y'know what? It sounds so weird to say this
我今天跟珍妮斯在一起很开心
but, I just had a great day with Janice!
-什么  -你说真的吗
- What?! - Are you serious?!
我跟她诉说
Yeah! I opened up to her about
我近来遭遇的倒霉事
all the terrible stuff that's been happening to me.
我说了好几个小时
I mean I talked for hours.
当有人专心听你倾诉时
It is amazing to have someone give you
感觉真好
such-such focused attention.
你何必找珍妮斯  你有我们
You don't need Janice for that, you've got us. We...
-鸭子先找到果仁奶油饼干  -不
- And the duck gets the Nutter-Butter! - No!
那才不是饼干  只是馊馄饨
Hey-hey that's not a Nutter-Butter, that's just an old Wonton!
裁判判定  是果仁奶油饼干
Judge rules, Nutter-Butter.
-很难判定  -是啊
- Ohh, tough call. - Yeah.
说真的  我坚信
But seriously, I strongly believe
我们该支持克林顿总统
that we should all support President Clinton.
和她的老公比尔
And her husband Bill.
你们的咖啡要加什么
So how do you kids like your coffee?
我不用  多谢了
Oh, none for me. Thanks.
我要一点点糖
Just a little bit of sugar.
那就让莫妮卡把手指伸进去
Well, maybe I'll bring it out and have Monica stick her finger in it.
应该就会甜了
That oughta sweeten it up, huh?
你那样笑怎么不会头痛
How does that laugh not give you a headache?
久了就习惯了
Oh, you get used to it.
我不觉得我会习惯
Y'know, I-I-I don't think that I can.
希望你别介意  我以后不会陪你应酬了
So if you don't mind, maybe this will be it for me on the work things.
上司说笑话我就笑  这有什么啊
So I laugh at my boss's jokes, what's the big deal?
如果能跟我尊敬的男友在一起
I'd rather hang out with a sniveling work weasel guy
我干嘛陪一个没尊严的马屁精
when I can be hanging out with my boyfriend who I actually respect.
我得为卡拉煮的咖啡道歉
Uh, I gotta apologize for Kara's coffee.
我真同情这咖啡  如果打架的话
Y'know, I feel sorry for it if it ever got in a fight,
完全没能力自卫(not strong指咖啡不够浓)
it's not strong enough to defend itself.
宾  你听到我的话了吗
Did you hear what I said Bing?
什么
What?
那个笑话啊  你是怎么了
The joke Bing. What's the matter with you?
我只是觉得不好笑
Well, I-I just didn't think it was funny sir.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我只是...
Well, I just...
亲爱的  我觉得你没听懂
Honey, I just don't think that you understood the joke.
是吗
Really?
真的很有趣
Yeah! I mean it was really funny,
只是你没明白
I-I just don't think you got it.
卡拉煮的咖啡很淡
You see Kara's coffee is-is-is weak tasting,
但道格是用双关说它很虚弱
okay? But-but what Doug did was-was imply that it was weak physically.
现在你懂了吗
You get it now honey?
我懂了
I think I do!
谢谢你  莫妮卡
Thank you, Monica.
我想着该帮你一把
I thought you could use the help.
咖啡打架
Coffee in a fight!
瑞秋  我可以在这里看漫画吗
Hey Rach! Hey, you mind if I read my comic books in here?
当然可以  怎么了
Sure! Why?
钱德勒和莫妮卡在那边
Oh well, Chandler and Monica are over there
我很难专心
and it's kinda hard to concentrate.
什么  她刚打电话来说她要加班
What?! She just called and said that she was gonna be working late!
她一直骗我  够了
She keeps lying to me! That's it! Y'know what?
我现在就过去揭穿他们
I'm just gonna go over there and confront them right now!
你是说  我现在还得讲种族主义的笑话吗
All right, so you're telling me that I have to tell racist jokes now?!
抱歉  我不擅长撒慌
Sorry! I'm just-I'm not very good at this!
我不会撒谎  尤其讨厌对瑞秋说谎
I'm a terrible liar and I hate having to lie to Rachel!
但我们还没准备好告诉大家
But we're not ready to tell yet!
我知道  只是从中学到现在
I know! It's just that...ever since high school
瑞秋和我之间都没有秘密
Rachel was the one person I told everything too. Y'know?
我很想念那种感觉  她是我最好的朋友
I miss that so much now. She's my best friend.
乔伊  天哪  瑞秋
Joey?! Oh my God, Rachel!
你在这里做什么
Wh-wh-what are you doing here?
事实上  我是过来借台灯的
Well, I was actually-I-I came over here to-to borrow this lamp.
我要看书  这样看得更清楚
To umm, look at my books, y'know, see them a little better.
很好
Okay great!
很好  我在钱德勒的房间
Great! Umm, well what-what I was doing in Chandler's room is that umm,
打扫卫生
I was cleaning it!
他花钱请我打扫
In fact, he pays me to clean it!
这样赚零花钱真是好办法
Oh! What a great way to earn some extra pocket money.
我之前告诉你我要加班
Y'know when I said to you earlier that I was at work
就是说的这份新工作
umm, I'm at my new work.
真是好工作  对吗
That's good enough. Right?
好了  我要去看书了
Okay, well umm, I'm gonna go look at my books!
我继续干活去了
I'll get back to my new job.
恭喜你找到新工作
Congratulations on your new job.
她可真好骗
Man, she is really gullible.
你们的咖啡
Here you go.
谢谢
Thanks!
我该走了
Actually, I should get going.
你确定吗  我陪你到多晚都行
Are you sure? Because I can stay out as late as you want.
我告诉过你  我被放长假了
I told you how I'm on sabbatical from work, right?
是的  你讲过了
Yes! Yes! You did!
现在又出什么问题了
What is wrong now?!
我点的不是这种
This isn't what I ordered!
老天  我的人生就不能顺利一点吗
Man! Can anything go right in my life?!
先是我的婚姻破裂  然后
First my marriage falls apart and then...
我知道  我知道  然后你无家可归
I know! I know! And then you lose your apartment!
你的工作没了
And then you lose your job!
你的前妻很快就再婚
And then your ex-wife gets married so fast!
现在咖啡又错了
And now the coffee-ahh!!
罗斯  我们得谈一谈
Ross, we need to talk.
好的  有时我觉得...
Okay. Sometimes I feel...
不是  我有话说
No-no-no, no. I'm going to talk.
我认为
I believe that
我们俩没戏唱了
the sun has set on our day in the sun.
-什么  -你是个好人  罗斯
- What? - You're a very sweet person Ross,
但很遗憾
unfortunately
我再也受不了听你诉苦了
I just don't think I can take another second of you whining!!
我没听错吧
Let-let me make sure I'm hearing this right,
你要和我结束
you're ending this with me
因为我太爱诉苦
because I'm too whiney?
你是说
So you're saying,
我太爱诉苦
I've become so whiney
让你珍妮斯
that I annoy you,
觉得很烦
Janice.
没错
Well yeah!!
我的天
OH...MY...GOD!!
你不要紧吧
Are you gonna be okay?
现在不要紧了
I am now.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
我搞定三分之二了
Well, I guess that's two out of three,
乔伊
Joey.
-伙计  我们得谈谈  -好的
- Dude, we got to talk. - Okay.
我只是想趁你听说之前
I just wanted to tell you something
告诉你
before you heard it from someone else
希望不会太奇怪
and I hope this isn't too weird, but uh,
我最近跟珍妮斯交往过
I had uh, a thing with Janice.
你不生气吗
What you're-you're not mad?
我干嘛生气
Why would I be mad?
因为这种事自有一套规矩
Well, because y'know there are certain rules about this kind of stuff.
不能追朋友的
You don't uh, you don't fool around with
旧情人
your uh, friend's ex-girlfriends
心上人  或是有亲属关系的人
or possible girlfriends or girls they're related to.
我很生气
I am mad!
但是你知道我会怎样吗  我会原谅你
But you know what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna forgive you!
因为这样才叫朋友
Because that's what friends do!
当朋友犯了你刚才念的那串禁忌时
They forgive their friends when they do everything you just said,
-朋友间会互相原谅  -谢谢
- all the things on the list there. - Thank you.
但是我要你记住
Well, but I want you to remember
我原谅了你
that I forgave you.
好的
Okay.
我还要你记住我免费收留你
I also want you to remember that I let you live here rent free!
好
All right.
我还要你记住我给过你
And, I want you to remember that I gave you
27块钱
twenty seven dollars.
无条件奉送
No strings attached.
要是你记不住
Now, if you can't remember that,
我们应该写下来  我们写下来吧
I think we should write it down-let's write it down!